(谨以此纪念Nicholas Courtney)
(准将的扮演者, 于2012年2月辞世)
(Attention all agents.
Incoming message from Grayhound Leader.)
（所有特工请注意. 收到来自灰狗队长的信息）
Professor Watkins disappeared.
Watkins 教授失踪了
Last known whereabouts: International Electromatics
已知的最后出现位置: 国际电气自动化公司
run by Managing Director Tobias Vaughn
该公司执行董事为 Tobias Vaughn
(International Electromatics London HQ)
国际电气自动化公司 伦敦总部
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who 1963
神秘博士(老版)
The Invasion
赛博人的入侵
(Whopix fan edit)
(粉丝剪辑版 http://wp.me/p1mHFo-lH )
(第一部分. 剪辑自原视频第六季第三集第1-4小集)
(Based on English subtitles from opensubtitles.org)
(时间轴/中文翻译: 巴蛮子sz)
Oh, yes, it could be 20th century.
哦, 是了, 可能是20世纪
What's the matter with the Tardis, Doctor?
It keeps going wrong all the time.
TARDIS 出什么问题了, 博士? 它总是出错
It merely needs an overhaul, Jamie,
just like any piece of machinery.
它只是需要一次大检修, Jamie, 就跟所有的机器一样
We might try and look up our old friend
Professor Travers in London.
我们试试联系我们在伦敦的老朋友 Travers 教授
- He might be able to help us, hmm?
- Yeah. Aye.
- 他也许能帮助我们, 嗯?   - 嗯, 是的
Always supposing he's not a baby or a schoolboy!
Now come along!
一直觉得他不是一个婴儿或者学童. 快过来吧
Let's just collect this circuit
我们收集一下电路
There.
那里
Yes. It's all right.
It's just a fault in the visual stabiliser circuit.
是的, 这没问题. 只是视觉稳定器电路有点故障
It's, uh... We'd better take that, too.
这是...我们最好把那个也带上
- Er... Can you give us a lift to London?
- Yes, I suppose so.
- 呃, 你能捎我们去伦敦吗?   - 行, 我觉得可以
DOCTOR: In you get.
你们进去
Thank you. Thank you very much.
谢谢你, 非常感谢
- DOCTOR: Here we are.  - Right
- 我们到啦  - 对了
Well, that's odd! It says ''Watkins''.
诶, 很奇怪, 上面写的 "Watkins"
(JAMIE) Must have the wrong house.
肯定搞错房子了
Well, the telephone directory
definitely said number 1 8.
啊, 电话号码簿上绝对写的是 18 号啊
We'll ask.
我们问问
(DOORBELL RINGING INCESSANTLY)
If you don't mind, I'm trying to work!
不介意的话, 我还要工作呢!
Oh. I'm sorry, miss, but we wondered
whether you could help us.
噢, 抱歉, 小姐. 但我们想问问你能否帮助我们
We wondered if...
我们想知道...
Oh, look, now the stupid thing's gone and jammed!
噢, 看, 这个蠢东西又卡住了
Oh, dear, perhaps I could help you.
噢, 亲爱的, 也许我可以帮你
Well, do you know anything about cameras?
哦, 你还懂一点相机?
Yes, a little. I see...
是的, 一点点. 我知道了...
Now I had it on automatic shutter.
现在我调到了自动快门模式
Taking photos of yourself?
在自拍呢?
Yes, then you interrupted me
and the stupid thing jammed!
是的, 然后你们打断了我, 这个破玩意儿就卡住了
Have you come to see my uncle?
He's not here.
你们是来找我叔叔的吧? 他现在不在这里
But who are you?
Friends of his? Fellow nuts?
但你们是谁? 他的朋友? 也是技术迷?
Please let me answer one question at a time.
且让我一个个地回答
Hey, you be careful with that thing.
It cost me a fortune.
嘿, 你小心弄这个东西, 它花了我不少钱
It's all right. It's a very simple mechanism.
没事的, 非常简单的机制
- Who is your uncle?  - Professor Watkins.
- 你叔叔是谁?   - Watkins 教授
Oh.
哦
Then Professor Travers doesn't live here?
那 Travers 教授不住在这里?
Well, he did. He left about a month ago.
哦, 以前是. 他大概一个月前离开了
Gone to America for a year with his daughter.
跟他女儿一起去非洲待一年
Oh, that's just great!
噢, 那太棒了!
My uncle worked at the Cavendish lab.
我叔叔在 Cavendish 实验室工作
He wanted to do some work so Professor Travers said
他想做点工作, 于是 Travers 教授说
he could use his daughter's lab here.
他可以用他女儿的这个实验室
And I moved in because I got kicked
out of my studio last week.
而我搬进来是因为我上周被踢出我的工作室了
What field of science is your uncle in?
你叔叔研究的是哪个领域?
Oh, I don't know,
he's in applied physics or something.
哦, 我不知道. 他是搞应用物理什么的吧
Always messing around with computers
and things. Complete nut.
总是在摆弄电脑这些. 完全的疯子
Well, that is fortunate.
Perhaps he might be able to help us.
哦, 那很幸运啊, 也许他可以帮助我们
- Is he at home?  - No.
- 他在家吗?   - 不在
- Well, where is he?
- Well, how do I know? I'm not his keeper.
- 那, 他在哪儿?   - 哦, 我怎么知道? 我不是他的管家
- Hey, have you fixed it?
- Oh, yes, that's all right.
- 嘿, 你修好了吗?   - 哦, 是的, 没事了
- That's really great, thanks!  - Miss...
- 真是太好了, 谢谢!   - 小姐...
Hey!
嘿!
That's a jolly outfit.
Would you mind posing for me?
这真是件漂亮的衣服. 你介意摆个姿势给我吗?
- What?  - Look. Just stand there.
- 什么?   - 喏, 就站那里
- Miss!  - Isobel.
- 小姐!   - 我叫 Isobel
Yeah, okay. Now just stand here.
Now get... Head over the shoulder.
对, 好. 就站在那里. 现在...把头朝肩膀过去一点
Have you any idea
when your uncle is going to be back?
知道你叔叔什么时候回来吗?
No, he left about a week ago.
I haven't seen him since.
不, 他大概一周前走的, 从那之后我就没见过他
A week?
一周?
Yeah, he was prattling on about some
new invention, or something or other,
是, 他一直在叨叨什么新发明, 不知道是什么东西
and having the chance to develop it.
Now... Not you.
说有机会来研究它了. 现在...不是你
- Oh.  - ISOBEL: Okay. Now.
- 噢  - 好, 现在
Can't you get in touch with him?
你能联系上他吗?
No, I tried.
不能, 我试过
I wanted to borrow a couple of quid
off him in a hurry,
我想找他借几镑救救急
but, well, they said
he wasn't available for phone calls.
但是, 他们说他没法接电话
They! Now... Now who is ''they''?
他们! 说说..."他们"是谁?
Just get that, will you? I don't know.
拿着这个, 好吗? 我不知道
International Electric, something or other.
好像是叫＂国际电子＂, 好像是吧
International Electromatics?
国际电气自动化公司?
Yes, probably.
是, 像是
You mean your uncle has gone to
work for these people?
你是说你叔叔去为这些人工作了?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Well, surely we can get in touch with him.
- 嗯哼  - 那, 我们当然可以联系上他了
Well, you can try telephoning,
but I doubt if you'll get any joy.
是, 你可以试着打打电话, 但我怀疑你不会得到好结果
Oh, phone's in the hall and
the number's scribbled on the wall.
哦, 电话就在大厅里, 号码写在墙上呢
Thank you.
谢谢你
Hey. Don't go.
嘿, 不要走
I don't often get the chance of
photographing a real model.
我并不是总有机会能给一个真正的模特拍照片
Oh, all right.
噢, 好吧
Come on. Let's get you fixed up with some gear!
快来, 我们来给你拍几张好看的(?)
WOMAN: International Electromatic Company.
State your business.
国际电气自动化公司. 请陈述你的目的
I would like, please,
to speak with Professor Watkins.
我想要, 请帮忙, 与 Watkins 教授通话
One moment.
等一下
- Party not available.
- Oh, yes. You see, but this is very important.
- 当事人不在  - 噢, 这样. 你看, 这事非常重要
Party not available.
当事人不在
- Yes, but I must speak with him.
- Party not available.
- 是的, 但我必须同他通话  - 当事人不在
- But this is an automatic answering device!
- 当事人不在  - 这是一台自动应答设备!
Ah, shut up, you stupid machine!
啊, 闭嘴, 你个愚蠢的机器!
- So, now what?
- There's only one thing for it!
- 那, 现在怎办?   - 就只有一件事可做了!
We'll have to go there ourselves.
我们只能自己去那里
Okay, that's fabulous, just keep it like that.
好, 那样很漂亮, 就这样保持住
Great. Any luck?
很好. 运气如何?
No, it was a stupid simple-minded
computer answering service.
不怎样, 只有一个愚蠢而死脑筋的电脑应答服务
Well, what do we do now?
那, 我们现在怎么做?
Well, Jamie and I are going to this place.
Come on, Zoe.
Jamie 和我打算去那个地方. 来吧, Zoe
Oh, no, thanks. I think I'll stay here.
It's great fun.
哦, 不, 谢谢. 我想我还是待在这里, 这很有意思
You look like a chicken with all those feathers on!
你穿上那些衣服就像一只小鸡!
Well, come on, Jamie. Oh, the address?
好, 来吧, Jamie. 哦, 地址有吗?
- Oh, that's scribbled on the wall, too.
- DOCTOR: Oh, thank you.
- 哦, 也在墙上写着呢  - 哦, 谢谢你
Do you not write anything down on paper at all?
你是什么都不写在纸上吗?
Well, I'd only lose it if I did.
要是我写在纸上的话, 只会把它弄丢
Writing on a wall is much safer.
You can't lose a wall, can you?
写在墙上安全多了. 你不可能弄丢一堵墙, 是吧?
No.
不能
HQ are checking now. Where are they?
总部在检查了, 他们在哪儿?
Gone round the back, down the side alley.
从后面绕过去了, 在旁边那个小巷里
It's a dead end, isn't it?
So they've got to come out this way!
那是条死路, 对吧. 所以他们还是会从这条路出来!
If they come out.
那得假设他们会出来
Come and sit down, gentlemen.
过来坐下, 先生们
DOCTOR: Thank you.
谢谢你
- You can go, Packer.  - Yes, sir.
- 你可以走了, Packer  - 好的, 先生
I must apologise for Packer's
crude devotion to duty.
Packer 只知道忠于职守, 我必须为他的粗鲁道歉
But your method of entry into my building
was rather...unconventional, wasn't it?
但你们进入我这大楼的方式也是相当地...打破传统了, 是不?
- Aye, well, there was no need for all that...
- Jamie!
- 是, 嗯, 没有必要费那个劲...  - Jamie!
...gas and stuff.
...这些虚假的客套
I think perhaps it is we
who should be apologising to you, Mr...
我觉得应该是我们向你道歉, 先生...
Vaughn. Tobias Vaughn.
Vaughn. 我叫 Tobias Vaughn.
I'm the Managing Director
of International Electromatics.
我是国际电气自动化公司的执行董事
Your business must be very pressing
to force you to such extremes.
你们的事情肯定非常紧迫, 才迫使你们采取了如此极端的手段
Yes, it is.
是的, 的确
- Concerning Professor Watkins?
- How did you know?
- 与 Watkins 教授有关吗?   - 你怎么知道?
My computer. It reported directly to me.
我的电脑. 它直接向我报告了
Oh, I see.
噢, 我明白了
You've gone to a lot of trouble for nothing, you know.
你们费尽周折却是徒劳, 知道吧
The Professor's working on an experiment
and refuses to see anyone.
教授正忙于一项实验, 拒绝见任何人
Ah, well. We only want to talk to him, you see.
啊, 其实, 我们只是想同他说几句话, 你看
Perhaps I can help.
也许我能帮上忙
No, I don't think so, thank you very much.
不, 我不觉得, 非常感谢
Oh, come on, Doctor,
it's only a couple of electronic circuits.
噢, 快点, 博士. 只是一些电子线路
(GRUNTING)
Circuits? Electronic circuits?
电路? 电子线路?
My technicians are the best in the world.
我的技术人员是这个世界最好的
I'm sure they'd be able to assist you.
我确定他们可以帮到你
- Show me the circuits.  - Well, I...
- 把电路给我看看  - 这个, 我...
Please, I'd like to help.
拜托, 我想帮忙
As you say, rather complex.
如你所说, 相当复杂
- However, I'm sure we'll be able to help you.
- Yes. You see...
- 然而, 我确定我们能帮助你  - 是的, 你看...
I'll have them sent to my workshops immediately.
我会安排人马上送到我的工作间
- Oh, how very kind.  - Not at all.
- 噢, 太给力了  - 不用
Professor Watkins is a valued colleague.
Any friend of his is... Oh.
Watkins 教授是一位重要的同事. 他的任何朋友都是...噢
- Have you got one of these, young man?
- No, what is it?
- 这个东西你有吗, 年轻人  - 没有, 是什么?
Surely you've seen them about.
They're disposable transistor radios.
你肯定见过它们. 它们是便携性晶体管收音机
One of our latest products. Most popular.
我们最新的一项产品, 非常畅销
We've sold 10 million in this country alone. Here.
我们仅仅在这个国家就买了一千万个. 给你
Compensation for the treatment
you received from the worthy Packer.
作为对你的补偿, 考虑到 Packer 对你的招待不周
Thank you. How does it work?
谢谢你, 它是怎么打开的?
(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Yes, that's how you turn it off, Jamie.
是的, 这样你就可以关掉它了, Jamie
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm afraid I have an urgent appointment.
现在, 如果你们没意见, 恐怕我还有一个紧急会议
Yes, of course. Come along, Jamie.
好, 当然了. 来吧, Jamie
Packer will meet you
and show you the way out, Mr...
Packer 会过来, 带你们出去, 这位...
- Doctor. Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
- 博士. 再见  - 再见, 博士
Goodbye, Mr Vaughn, and thank you for the radio.
再见, Vaughn 先生. 谢谢你的收音机
Not at all.
不用谢
- Packer?  - Yes, Mr Vaughn?
- Packer?  - 什么事, Vaughn 先生?
Show our visitors off the premises, will you?
带我们的客人离开, 好吗?
Very good, sir.
很好, 先生
PACKER: The next time,
read the notice on the door.
下一次,读一下门上的警告
JAMIE: Oh, don't tell me you can read as well.
What else do you do?
哦, 别告诉我你也识字. 你还会干什么?
Jamie!
Jamie!﻿
That fellow's not what he seems.
那个家伙并不是他看起来那样
That big idiot? Oh, don't worry.
I'll soon sort...
那个傻大个? 不用担心. 我很快就能...
No, no, no. I mean Vaughn.
不, 不, 不. 我是说 Vaughn
Oh, and he's got a forked tail and wee horns.
噢, 他有一条分叉的尾巴, 头上还有角
Oh, I'm not joking, Jamie.
哦, 我不是在开玩笑, Jamie
Underneath all that charm,
there was something odd.
外表上很有魅力, 但底下总觉得有点古怪
Sinister. Almost inhuman.
很邪恶. 感觉不像人类
To All Agents: PRIORITY ONE ALERT
by Direct Order of A.G.L-S.
通知所有特工: 最高优先级警报, 来自 A.G.L-S 的直接命令
Locate and Detain THE DOCTOR,
Repeat - THE DOCTOR
找到并扣留博士. 重复 - 博士
Target sited in vicinity of IE building...
目标曾经在 IE 公司大楼附近出现...
Packer.
Packer﻿
Yes, Mr Vaughn?
什么事, Vaughn 先生
Packer, those two uninvited guests
we had this morning,
Packer, 今天早上那两位不速之客
- I assume they were photographed?
- Yes, sir.
- 我估计给他们拍照了吧?   - 是的, 先生
Have some prints taken and sent up to me.
打印几份, 送到我这里来
- Well, what do we do now, Doctor?
- Accept the situation, Jamie.
- 怎样, 我们现在怎么做, 博士?   - 接受现状, Jamie
Nothing else we can do.
我们没什么可做的
You're still worried about
your two friends, aren't you? Why?
你还是担心你的两个朋友, 是不? 为什么?
Oh, I don't know.
噢, 我不知道
I've just got this feeling
that something's happened to them.
我只是有这种感觉, 有事发生在他们身上了
- Why on earth should it have?
- No reason at all, really.
- 到底为什么会有事呢?   - 完全没理由, 真的
It's not a logical conclusion, just intuition.
不是一个有逻辑的结论, 只是直觉
Well, I'll tell you what we'll do, then.
好, 那我告诉你我们该怎么做
- We'll go right out after them, okay?
- Oh, yes, please.
- 我们这就出去找他们, ＯＫ?   - 哦, 好
But we'd better leave a note for them,
但我们最好给他们留个信息
just in case they come back when we're not here.
以免他们回来时我们又不在
Would you mind telling us what all this is about?
你能否告诉我们, 这都是怎么一回事吗?
- You'll find out, sir.
- Sir?
- 你会明白的, 先生  - 先生?
- All right, Benton, thank you.  - Sir.
- 没事了, Benton, 谢谢你  - 是
- NAAFI break, sir?  - Very well.
- NAAFI 有间歇了(?),  长官?   - 很好
(NAAFI: 英国陆海空三军合作所)
How nice to see you again, Doctor.
很高兴再见到你, 博士
It's Colonel Lethbridge-Stewart!
是 Lethbridge-Stewart 上校!
Ah, Brigadier now. I've gone up in the world.
啊, 现在是准将了. 我在这里升职了
Of course, the Yetis. We met you in the...
当然了, 雪怪那回, 我们跟你碰过面, 在...
That's right, McCrimmon, in the Underground.
对的, McCrimmon, 在地下
Must be four years ago now.
肯定是四年以前了
That long. It only seems like
a couple of weeks ago, doesn't it?
那么久? 感觉好像才几个星期而已, 是吧?
I've told you over and over again, Jamie.
Time is relative.
我跟你说了一遍又一遍, Jamie. 时间是相对的
Are you still making a nonsense of it, Doctor,
in your... What was it called?
你还在讲这些笑话吗, 博士, 在你的...它是叫什么来着?
- Tardis?  - Yes, we're still travelling. Yes.
- TARDIS?  - 是的, 我们还在旅行, 是的
Yes, Mr Travers told me all about it.
是, Travers 先生都说给我听了
It's, um... Well, it's...
那是个, 嗯...怎么说, 是个...
To say the least, an unbelievable machine.
简单说吧, 一台不可思议的机器
DOCTOR: Any more unbelievable than the Yetis, hmm?
比雪怪还不可思议吗, 嗯?
No, true. I'm not quite
so much of a sceptic as I was
没有, 的确. 我不再像以前那样怀疑这些
- since that little escapade.
- But what's all this,
- 就自打上次灵异事件之后  - 但这些都是什么意思?
and why all the cloak and dagger stuff
to bring us here?
为什么这些带着斗篷和剑的家伙把我们带到这里来?
Yes, I'm sorry about that, but my chaps have to
be a bit melodramatic in their methods.
是的, 对此我表示抱歉. 但我的人必须在执行力上强一些
But I'll explain. Oh, do sit down.
但我会解释的. 哦, 请坐下吧
- Thank you.  - How nice.
- 谢谢你  - 很好
(WHIRRING)
Has the information been considered?
这个信息已经考虑过了吗?
COMMUNICATOR: The images of the two humans
这两个人的图像
have been analysed and registered.
已经被分析和记录了
They are known and are hostile.
他们是已知的敌人
Hostile? How can that be?
敌人? 怎么可能呢?
Have you been on Earth before?
你们以前到过地球吗?
No, they have been recognised
没有, 他们已经被认出来了
They are dangerous and must be destroyed.
他们很危险, 必须被消灭
Yes, well, since the Yeti do,
是的, 自从雪怪事件以后
I've been in charge of an independent intelligence group
我就负责了一个独立的情报组
that we call UNIT, that's
United Nations Intelligence Taskforce.
我们叫它 UNIT, 也就是＂联合国情报行动组＂
You mean you're like a... A world secret police?
你是说, 你就像一个...秘密的世界警察?
Not quite. We don't actually arrest people,
we just investigate them.
不大对. 我们实际上并不逮捕人, 我们只是调查他们
What about us? I mean, you arrested us.
那我们呢? 我是说, 你逮捕了我们
Not really.
并不是
You see, my men were keeping a watch on
the International Electromatic Headquarters
你看, 我的人一直在监视国际电气自动话公司的总部
when you two showed up.
这时候你们俩出现了
I've been keeping a check
on everyone going in that building.
我一直在核查进入那栋大楼的每一个人
Your photographs were transmitted
to this Headquarters and I recognised you.
你们的照片传到总部, 我认出了你们
Well, what's so odd about
people going into the building?
那, 进入那栋大楼的有什么奇怪的?
Oh, nothing odd about them going in.
噢, 进入的人倒没有什么奇怪
The problem is some of them haven't come out.
问题在于有些人一直没有出来
BRIGADIER: This is Gordon Jones,
lecturer in physics, Churchill College, Cambridge.
这位是 Gordon Jones, 物理学讲师, 剑桥丘吉尔学院
Next one's a chap I knew at Sandhurst,
old Billy Rutlidge.
下一个是我在 Sandhurst 就认识的, 老 Billy Rutlidge
(Sandhurst 是英国陆军官校所在地)
He's got himself a very cushy number
at the Ministry of Defence.
他给自己在国防部找了一个待遇很不错的岗位
And all these people went into the building,
the IE building, and didn't come out.
这些人都走进了那栋大楼, IE 的大楼, 然后没有出来
No, no, most of them came out again,
不, 不, 他们中大多数人又出来了
but there was something definitely odd
about them when they did.
但他们出来的时候绝对都有些古怪
Odd?
古怪?
Ah, yes, Miss Watkins.
啊, 是, Watkins 小姐
You're concerned about your uncle, aren't you?
你在担心你的叔叔, 是吗?
I'd like to know where he is, yes.
是, 我想知道他在那里
He's perfectly well, I assure you,
although a little, uh...
他非常好, 我可以向你保证, 虽然有一点...
uncooperative at the moment.
目前来说不太合作
Your visit here is most opportune.
你们来的时机相当好
I think that you can be very useful to me.
我觉得你会对我非常有用
Me? But... But how?
我? 但是...怎么会?
Your uncle needs to be ''persuaded''
to continue his work for me.
你叔叔需要一点＂说服＂工作, 才能继续为我服务
But I can't do anything about that.
但我对此做不了什么
No.
不能
But I can. Now...
但我可以. 现在...
Packer, I'd like you to take care
of these two young ladies, please.
Packer, 我想请你照顾一下这两位年轻的女士
Take them!
把她们带走!
(GIRLS PROTESTING)
Um, Brigadier, tell me more about this
唔, 准将, 多告诉我一些信息
International Electromatics setup.
关于这个国际电气自动化公司的情况
Well, there isn't much to tell.
这个, 没有太多可说的
The head of the group
is a man named Tobias Vaughn.
这个组织的头儿是一个叫做 Tobias Vaughn 的人
Oh, yes, we've met him. A nice man.
哦, 是的, 我已经见过他了. 一个不错的人
- He gave me this.  - Jamie.
- 他给了我们这个  - Jamie﻿
- Oh, yes, that's just the small stuff.
- Put it away.
- 噢, 是的, 就是这种小东西  - 把它收起来
They control practically
all of the major computer lines.
他们实际上控制了几乎所有主要的电脑生产线
They made their real breakthrough
in micromonolithic circuit designing.
他们在微型单晶片电路设计方面还真有些突破
Undercutting practically everyone else
on the market.
事实上把市场上的其他对手都挤出去了
But what's your interest in this?
但你们为什么对这个感兴趣?
Well, I knew a little about Vaughn
before his sudden success.
在 Vaughn 突然成功之前, 我对它知之甚少
I put out a routine check on him and
we came up with one or two things of interest.
我对他进行了例行检查, 发现了一两项感兴趣的事情
Like the disappearance of Professor Watkins.
比如 Watkins 教授的失踪
- Yes.  - Ah, see.
- 是的  - 啊, 明白了
I... I don't suppose you have any authority
我...我觉得你们没有得到授权
to search the building, have you?
能够搜查这栋大楼, 有吗?
No, Vaughn's too powerful,
he's got too many top people on his side.
不, Vaughn 很有手段. 在高层里面有太多人站在他这边
You see, Doctor, I daren't make a move against him
unless I have good reason to do so.
你看, 博士, 我不敢对他有任何动作, 除非我有很好的理由
Well, it looks to me,
if Jamie and I want to find the Professor,
哦, 在我看来, 如果 Jamie 和我想要去找教授
we'll have to do it in our own way.
我们就只能用自己的方法
That's about the sum of it.
总体来说就是这样
However, should you find yourself
in any difficulty...
但是, 如果你们遇到任何困难...
Sergeant Walters!
Walters 中士
- Yes, sir?  - Got a TM-45 handy?
- 是, 长官?   - 手上有 TM-45?
Yes, sir. Right here.
有, 长官, 就在这里
- Is that a tank?  - Oh, no, no.
- 那是一架塔克吗?   - 噢, 不, 不是
My units are on constant alert,
我的部队会保持警惕
so should you find yourselves in any trouble,
所以如果你们发现自己遇到任何麻烦
- you can just give us a call.
- Jolly good!
- 就可以呼叫我们  - 太好了
- Here you are, sir.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
- 给你, 长官  - 谢谢你, 中士
Now, this is a small transceiver,
看, 这是一个小型收发器
range of about fifty miles on a set frequency.
在预定频率上有效范围大概是50英里
Just press this button and ask for me.
只要按这个钮就可以找我就可以了
Oh, yes, that's splendid! Yes.
This should come in very handy.
噢, 好, 这太棒了! 是的, 这应该非常方便
Call me anytime. I'm usually available.
随时呼我, 我一般都在
No. They must have gone out.
不, 他们肯定已经走了
Zoe?
Zoe?﻿
Isobel?
Isobel?﻿
Probably gone for a walk.
可能出去散步了
Look, Jamie, sandwiches. I'm hungry.
看, Jamie, 三明治. 我饿了
- Want one?  - Thank you.
- 来一个吗?   - 谢谢你
You know, Doctor, that chap Mr Vaughn
doesn't seem such a bad man.
知道吗, 博士, Vaughn 那个家伙看着并不像是个坏人
(TURNS RADIO ON)
Oh, Jamie!
噢, Jamie!
How can I think when you've got that thing on?
你把这玩意儿打开我还怎么思考?
Hey!
嘿!
All right, all right.
好吧, 好吧
- Don't break it.  - All right!
- 别弄坏了  - 没事的!
I just want to have a look at it, that's all.
我只是想看一眼这东西, 仅此而已
Oh, yes.
噢, 对了
- It's an interesting little piece...
- What?
- 这是个有意思的小东西...  - 什么?
Well, well, well.
好, 好, 好
What have we here?
看看我们这有什么?
What do you mean, ''What have we here?''
你什么意思, ＂看看我们这里有什么＂
There's a micromonolithic circuit
in the back plate of this radio.
在这个收音机的后面板上有一个微型单晶片电路
Well, what's that?
哦, 那是什么?
It's a very complex circuit in miniature.
是一种非常复杂的电路, 做得很小
What's so odd about that, then?
那又有什么奇怪的?
It has nothing to do with the radio,
as far as I can see.
就我的观察, 它跟收音机功能无关
- Oh, Doctor, just put it back together again!
- All right.
- 噢, 博士, 还是把它放回去吧!   - 好吧
I don't suppose Zoe would have
left a note, do you?
我觉得 Zoe 不会留一张字条, 你说呢?
No, I can't see anything.
Well, you might at least help me look for it.
我也什么都没看见. 是了, 你至少可以帮我找一下
I suggest we try the wall.
我建议我们看看墙上
Eh?
嗯?
Isobel never writes anything on paper.
Isobel 从不把东西写在纸上
- You can't lose a wall, remember?
- Oh.
- ＂你总不会弄丢一堵墙＂, 记得吗?   - 哦
Ah! ''Tired of waiting.
啊!  ＂等得不耐烦了
''Gone to IE offices to look for you.
Zoe and Isobel.''
＂出发去 IE 的办公室找你们. Zoe 和 Isobel＂
Jamie! We better go after them.
Jamie! 我们最好去找她们
How long ago did they go in?
他们多久以前进去的?
BENTON: Some time ago, sir.
有段时间了, 长官
Tracy followed them as far as the official
boundary of the railway sidings.
Tracy 跟着他们一直到了铁轨的外墙边上
They went in about an hour ago.
他们半个小时前进去的
- Is Tracy still round there?
- Yes, sir.
- Tracy 还在那附近吗?   - 是的, 长官
- Right, stick around for a while.
- Just a minute, sir.
- 好, 继续还待在那里  - 等一下, 长官
Yes, what is it, Benton?
好, 什么事, Benton?
The Doctor and the boy.
They're coming out, sir, with Vaughn.
是博士和那个男孩, 他们出来了, 长官, 同 Vaughn 一起
They've all got into Vaughn's private car.
他们都进了 Vaughn 的私人轿车
Oh, they're driving off, sir.
噢, 他们开走了, 长官
- Is any force being used?
- No. Not that I can see.
- 有武力胁迫吗?   - 没有, 我没有见到.
Packer was there,
but it all seemed very friendly to me.
Packer 也在, 但在我看来似乎还比较友好
Shall we follow?
我们要跟住吗?
No, I'll have them tracked more discreetly.
Over and out.
不, 我会安排更加隐蔽的跟踪. 完毕, 挂了
- Sergeant Walters.  - Yes, sir?
- Walters 中士  - 是, 长官
- Alert all area patrols in section three.
- Yes, sir.
- 通知第三组的所有区域巡逻队  - 是, 长官
- Did you hear all that, Jimmy?
- I did, sir.
- 你都听到了吗, Jimmy?  - 听到了, 长官
Look, we'll get you aboard a chopper,
and you can rendezvous with the tracking agent.
我给你安排一架直升飞机, 你就可以与负责跟踪的人汇合了
All right, sir.
好的, 长官
(ROTORS WHIRRING)
Yes, they've just gone into the IE area, sir.
好, 他们已经进入了 IE 的区域, 长官
- Shall I follow?  - No, circle the area.
- 我要跟进去吗?   - 不, 在那里盘旋.
We can't really do anything
until we get a request from the Doctor.
除非我们收到博士的请求, 否则我们什么也不能做
- Standing by, sir.
- And, Jimmy, keep out of sight.
- 待命中, 长官  - 还有, Jimmy, 保持在他们视线之外
If Vaughn's private army see you,
they might well get the wind up,
如果 Vaughn 的私人武装看到你们, 他们可能会搞事
and that might make things rather unhealthy
for the Doctor and the boy.
这可能会让局面对博士和那个小伙子不利
Hey!
嘿
- Doctor, it's...  - Confusing, isn't it?
- 博士, 这...  - 分不清了, 是吧?
It's exactly the same as your office in London.
这跟你在伦敦的办公室一模一样
In all basic essentials, yes, it is.
所有基本要素都是一样的, 是的
That's the secret of my success, you see.
这是我成功的秘诀, 知道吗
Uniformity. Duplication.
匀称, 一致
My whole empire is based on that principle.
我的整个商业帝国都基于这个原则
The very essence of business efficiency.
业务效率的精髓
- Do sit down.  - DOCTOR: Oh, how kind.
- 请坐下  - 哦, 有心了
I must say I'm rather glad
we have this opportunity to talk.
我必须要说我很高兴我们有机会进行这次谈话
Really?
真的?
I should, of course, be angry with you.
当然, 其实我应该生你们的气
You've thwarted my elaborate
security precautions twice.
你们挫败了我精心制定的安全预防措施, 两次
- I'd like to know why.
- Oh, that's quite simple.
- 我想知道为什么  - 哦, 那很简单
I hate computers
and refuse to be bullied by them.
我讨厌电脑, 拒绝被他们欺负
Your young friend Zoe.
你们的年轻朋友 Zoe
- Well, what about her?
- Well, she appears to have the same instincts.
- 哦, 她怎么了  - 她似乎也有同样的直觉
She so confused one of my computers
she ruined its memory store.
所以她搞烂了我们的一台电脑, 毁坏了它的内存记忆
So that's why your thugs
dragged her and Isobel away.
所以这就是为什么你那些暴徒会把她和 Isobel 拖走
My dear young man, I wasn't angry with her.
我亲爱的年轻人, 我没生她的气
On the contrary, I found the incident quite amusing.
恰恰相反, 我发现这个事情很有意思
She's a remarkable girl.
她是个不寻常的女孩儿
And you, Doctor, are obviously a man
of no mean scientific ability.
而你, 博士, 显然是个科学能力不一般的人
Why do you say that?
你为什么这么说?
Well, my research department
found these quite fascinating.
哦, 我的研究部发现这些东西很吸引人
There's a totally illogical factor
in their construction.
在它们的结构里面有一个完全不符合逻辑的部分
Are they of your own invention?
这是你自己发明的吗?
Ah, you're determined to guard your secret, I see.
啊, 你下定了决心要保守你的秘密, 我明白了
I don't blame you,
and I promise not to pry any more.
我不怪你, 而且我保证不再打听了
- In fact, I'll do all I can to help you.
- Oh, how kind.
- 事实上, 我会竭尽所能帮助你  - 噢, 你真好
Now, you say you came here
looking for Professor Watkins
现在, 你们说来这里是找 Watkins 教授
because you thought he might be able to help you.
说是因为你们觉得他也许可以帮助你们
Yes.
是的
Well, then I'll try to persuade him
to put aside his work and, um,
好, 那我会试试, 看能否说服他把工作放一放
concentrate his efforts on your behalf.
聚焦到你的事情上
Make yourself at home.
请随意
Hey, look, you're not going to trust him, are you?
嘿, 听着, 你没打算相信他吧, 是吗?
- I mean, what about Zoe and Isobel?
- I haven't forgotten them, Jamie.
- 我是说, Zoe 和 Isobel 怎么办?   - 我没忘记她们, Jamie
They're in that box. I'm sure of it.
她们就在那里面, 我敢肯定
Jamie, we're not going to help Zoe
by annoying Mr Vaughn, are we?
Jamie, 我们惹恼 Vaughn 先生并不能帮上 Zoe, 对吗?
I don't think you can annoy that man
even if you wanted to.
我觉得就是你想, 你也没法惹恼那个家伙
He's being as nice as pie.
他的脾气很好
He's too nice.
他有点太好了
- Yeah, but why should he be?
- I don't know.
- 是, 但为什么他会这样?   - 我不知道
He's a little bit too interested
in these circuits for my liking.
他对这些电路有点太感兴趣了, 我不喜欢
Hey, do you think he knows
about the Tardis, then?
嘿, 那, 你觉得他知道 TARDIS 的事吗?
Well, I don't see how he could do.
我看不出他怎么能知道
No, well, perhaps this Professor Watkins
will be able to tell us what's going on around here.
不能. 也许这位 Watkins 教授能告诉我们这里在搞什么
- Yes, but that's what's worrying me.
- What?
- 是, 但让我困扰的也是这个  - 什么?
Well, if Vaughn has anything to hide...
是这样, 如果 Vaughn 有事情瞒着我们...
why is he letting us talk to Watkins?
他为什么会让我们跟 Watkins 谈话?
I'd think about it if I were you, Professor.
如果我是你, 我就会考虑的, 教授
After all, she is a pretty girl.
It'd be a shame to spoil all that.
毕竟, 她是个漂亮的女孩儿, 破坏这一点的话就就太惭愧了
What a vicious sadist you are, Packer.
你是个多么恶毒的虐待狂啊, Packer
I don't believe you, anyway.
我不相信你, 不管怎样
I don't make idle threats, Professor,
as you well know.
我不会做无谓的威胁, 教授, 你是知道的
If you want to see that girl again in one piece,
如果你还想见到那个女孩儿完好无损话,
I suggest you do as Mr Vaughn asks.
我建议你按 Vaughn 先生要求的做
How do I know that you already
haven't harmed her, if you had got her.
我怎么知道你们还没有伤害她, 既然你们都抓住她了?
You can take my word for that, Professor.
你可以得到我对此的承诺, 教授
(LAUGHING) Your word.
你的承诺
I know just how much value I can place on that.
我可知道它值多少钱
Harsh words, Professor, harsh words.
话说过份了啊, 教授, 过份了
Any progress?
有什么进展?
- So you haven't yet completed the machine?
- No, and I don't intend to.
- 看来你还没有完成这个机器  - 没, 而且我也没打算完成
Oh, I think you will, Professor.
噢, 我想你会的, 教授
Much as I detest violence,
虽然我很讨厌暴力
I find it difficult to restrain Packer's
indisputable talent for persuasion.
我发现很难压制 Packer 那无可争辩的说服能力
Your niece is in our custody,
你侄女在我们的监管之下
and unless you do as I ask,
I shall hand her over to Packer.
除非你按我的要求去做, 否则我就把她交给 Packer
The choice is yours.
选择权在你
If I do cooperate, will you let her go?
如果我合作, 你们会放她走吗?
Oh, no, she's our guarantee,
but she'll come to no harm.
哦, 不会, 她是我们的保证人, 不过她不会受到伤害
All right.
好吧
- But I must see Isobel first.
- Of course.
但我必须先见到 Isobel  - 当然
Oh, there is just one other thing.
哦, 另外只有一件事了
Don't look at me so suspiciously,
my dear Professor.
别用这种怀疑的眼神看我, 亲爱的教授
It's merely that there are some friends
of yours here who wish to see you.
只不过这里有几位你的朋友想要见你
- Friends?
- Yes, they've gone to great pains to seek you out.
- 朋友?   - 是的, 他们费尽周折要把你找出来
But I haven't been allowed visitors
since I came here.
但自从我到这里来, 就不被允许会客
Why are you suddenly considerate?
你怎么突然这么贴心了?
I might tell them everything.
我可能把一切都告诉他们
Everything?
一切?
My dear Professor, you know nothing that can harm me.
亲爱的教授, 你不知道任何对我不利的信息
Besides, there's always Isobel
to consider, isn't there?
再说了, 总还得考虑 Isobel 吧, 是不?
- Or would you rather leave her to me?
- No, no, Packer.
- 或许你更愿意把她留给我?   - 不, 不, Packer
The Professor's going to do exactly as we ask.
教授会严格按我们要求的做
Aren't you?
对吧?
Yes, of course, I remember
Anne Travers telling me about you.
是的, 当然了, 我记得 Anne Travers 跟我说起过你
(Anne Travers 是老 Travers 教授的女儿,
在 05x05 The Web of Fear 一集中他们父女俩
与博士、UNIT一起对抗雪怪)
She was a student of mine,
you know, some years ago.
她是我的学生, 你知道, 多年以前
- Brilliant girl. Brilliant.  - Yes.
- 很有才华的女孩, 很有才华  - 是的
Yes, they went to America, didn't they?
是的, 他们去了美洲, 是吗?
Oh, Travers was getting past it a bit, you know,
哦, Travers 有点老了, 你知道
and Anne persuaded him to go to America with her.
Anne 说服了他跟她一起去美洲
Oh, yes.
哦, 是了
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么?
Well, it's a long story.
啊, 这就说来话长了
The strange Doctor
has been on another planet, Packer.
这个奇怪的博士到过其它星球, Packer
That's not possible!
那是不可能的
It is a fact, Packer.
这是事实, Packer
He has some sort of machine.
他有某种机器
Now let's see if we can
learn more about it, shall we?
现在我们来看看能不能了解到更多情况, 好吗?
Switch on, Packer.
打开吧, Packer
With sound.
声音也打开
So we went to see Mr Vaughn,
所以我们去找 Vaughn 先生
and he said that you were working
on something important.
他说你在做一个重要的项目
I see. That's why you wanted to
leave them alone together.
我明白了, 这就是为什么你要把他们俩单独留在一起
Exactly, Packer.
正是, Packer
(COMMUNICATOR HUMMING)
But the Doctor needed some help
on some electronic circuits that the Tardis had.
但博士需要有人帮忙弄一下 TARDIS 的电路板
- Really?  - Aye, aye.
- 真的?   - 是, 是
Jamie, Jamie. I don't think
the Professor wants to hear about that.
Jamie, Jamie, 我不觉得教授对这个感兴趣
Oh, on the contrary, what Anne told me
about the Tardis was most intriguing.
噢, 恰恰相反, Anne 所告诉我的那些 TARDIS 的事情是最吸引我的
I'd like to hear a lot more about it.
我想多听一点关于它的事情
Professor, I think I should warn you
教授, 我觉得我应该警告你
that Anne Travers allowed
her imagination to run a little wild.
Anne Travers 太放任她的想象力天马行空乱跑了
You mean to say that there is no such machine?
你是想说没有这样的机器?
- Of course there is...  - Jamie, I think
- 当然有...  - Jamie, 我觉得
there are other more important things
to talk about at the moment.
现在这时候还有更重要的事情需要讨论
Oh, I see, yes.
哦, 我明白了, 是的
Professor, tell us about what you're doing here.
教授, 告诉我们你在这里做些什么
Oh, it's very simple, really.
哦, 很简单的事情, 真的
I've been developing
a new kind of teaching machine.
我在研究一种新的教学机器
- Oh, yes? A teaching machine?
- What's it called?
- 哦, 是吗? 一种教学机器?   - 它叫做什么?
- I call it the Cerebraton Mentor.
- Oh, aye.
- 我把它叫做思维导师  - 哦, 是
The main difference from other teaching machines
它与其它教学机器的主要差别
is that it's able to induce
emotional changes in the subject.
就是它能诱导测试对象的情绪变化
JAMIE: Oh.
噢
Our friend the Doctor is a resourceful man.
我们的博士朋友是个足智多谋的人
No wonder our allies fear him.
怪不得我们的盟友害怕他
- Our allies know him?
- Oh, yes, I was ordered to destroy him.
- 我们的盟友知道他?   - 哦, 是的, 它们命令我消灭他
But first I must learn the secrets
of this extraordinary machine of his.
但首先我必须掌握他那台非凡机器的秘密
If you're ordered to destroy him...
如果它们的命令是要消灭他...
I don't take orders, Packer. I give them!
我不接受命令, Packer, 我只下发命令!
Now, I think the time has come
to stop playing games with this Doctor!
现在, 我觉得是时候停止与博士玩游戏了!
But what can we do?
但我们能怎么做?
If, as you say, they have got Isobel
and your young friend,
如果, 如你所说, 他们抓住了 Isobel 和你那年轻朋友
then we're entirely at their mercy.
那我们就完全得看他们脸色了
No, no, not entirely.
There's my friend the Brigadier, remember?
不, 不, 也不尽然. 还有我的准将朋友, 记得吗?
- Do you think he can help us?  - Possibly.
- 你觉得他能帮助我们?   - 很可能
But quickly, tell me, what is Vaughn up to?
但是快点, 告诉我, Vaughn 在图谋什么?
- What's he doing here?
- I know no more than you do.
- 他在这里做些什么?   - 我知道得不比你多
He's a ruthless man, without morals or principles.
他是个冷酷无情的人, 没有道德和原则
His object, I'm sure, is to get complete control
of the electronics industry of the world!
他的目标, 我肯定, 是要全面控制整个世界的电子工业!
I wonder.
我很好奇
I've a nasty feeling he's aiming
somewhat higher than that.
我有一种不好的感觉, 他有某种比这更高的目标
Doctor, quick, somebody's coming.
博士, 快, 有人来了
Don't bother, Doctor.
别费事了, 博士
Allow me.
让我来
Very ingenious. A simple magnet.
很天才啊, 一块简单的磁铁
I congratulate you.
我祝贺你
Oh, how kind.
哦, 谢谢
However, you must surely realise
但是, 你肯定明白
that it's forced me to consider
other methods to make you talk.
这会逼我考虑其它方法来让你说话
What are you going to do?
你打算做什么?
Your friend Zoe is due to arrive here shortly.
你的朋友 Zoe 很快就该到了
So you have got her!
Listen, if you've harmed her in any...
看来你抓了她! 听着, 如果你伤害她一根...
You may still be adolescent enough
to make idle threats, young man,
你可以继续幼稚地做些空洞的威胁, 年轻人
but I can assure you, I am not.
但我可以向你保证, 我就不会
I want your travel machine, Doctor.
我要你的旅行机器, 博士
Otherwise, I shall hand your friend Zoe
over to Packer.
否则, 我就会把你的朋友交给 Packer
It's a simple choice, and shouldn't take you
longer than an hour to consider.
这是个简单的选择, 应该不需要超过一个小时来考虑
Take them away, Packer.
把他们带走, Packer
- All right.  - All right.
- 好啦  - 好啦
Leave them to me. I'll take them.
把他们留给我, 我来处理
Now, Professor, I suggest you continue with your work.
现在, 教授, 我建议你继续你的工作
Oh, dear. You know, Jamie,
I've always been rather scared of lifts.
噢, 天. 你知道吗, Jamie, 我一直都很害怕电梯
Why?
为什么?
I never even like to start them.
我甚至从不喜欢启动它们
You will have to push the button for me.
你必须得替我按按钮了
Keep your mouth shut. Do as you're told.
闭上你的嘴. 按吩咐的做
- Yes, Jamie. Do as you're told.
- Oh, yes...
- 是的, Jamie, 按吩咐的做  - 哦, 好...
PACKER: Be quiet!
哦, 好...   - 安静!
Packer! Mr Packer,
I obviously can't let you hurt Zoe,
Packer! Packer 先生, 显然我不能让你伤害 Zoe
and so I'll have to tell you
all you want to know, now.
所以我只得把你们想知道的都告诉你们
You mean you're willing to talk?
你意思是你愿意说了?
Yes, I'm sure that Mr Vaughn would...
是的, 我确信 Vaughn 先生会...
- Oh, there he is now...
- Quick, Doctor.
- 哦, 他不来了吗...  - 快点, 博士
Your knife.
你的刀
Your knife. Give me your knife.
你的刀, 给我你的刀
- Why? What are you going to do?
- I'm going to try and break the circuit.
- 为什么? 你打算做什么?   - 我要试试能不能破坏电路
What would that do?
那又会怎样?
Well, it will either stop the lift
or send us out of control.
唔, 要么会让电梯停掉, 要么我们会失控掉下去
But we're six floors up.
但我们在六楼上啊
We'll have to take that risk.
Hold tight, here we go.
我们必须担这个风险. 抓紧了, 我们走
(CLATTERING)
- Why are you so gullible, Packer?
- Just wait till I get hold of them. I'll...
- 你怎么这么容易受骗, Packer?   - 等我抓到他们, 我要...
You'll do nothing!
I want them in one piece.
你什么也不要做. 我要他们安然无恙
There was a 50/50 chance, you know, Jamie.
这里有 50对50 的几率, 知道吧, Jamie
Yes, but what good has it done us?
哦, 但对我们有什么好处呢?
I mean, we're stuck here in this lift now.
我是说, 我们困在这个电梯里了
No. No, it's the lift that's stuck,
不, 不, 被困住的是电梯
not us. Look!
而不是我们. 看!
Hey, where does that lead to?
嘿, 那东西通到哪里?
Out into the lift shaft, I imagine.
Quickly, on me back.
通到电梯井外面, 我估计. 快点, 到我后面去
You know something?
You're a clever wee chappie!
你知道吗? 你是个聪明的家伙!
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHING)
Thank you, Jamie.
谢谢你, Jamie
Oh, my word!
哦, 老天
Well, that's a long way up, isn't it?
啊, 上去好远的路啊, 是不?
Oh, well, we better get cracking
before they realise what's happened, eh?
哦, 我们最好快点爬, 一会儿他们就发现了
- Perhaps I'd better shut this.
- Aye.
- 也许我最好关上这个  - 是啊
(DOCTOR GRUNTS)
Hey, Doctor, I've just been thinking.
嘿, 博士, 我刚才在想
What happens if they get the lift going
before we get to the top?
我们到达顶楼之前, 如果他们开动了电梯会怎么样?
- Oh, that's simple.  - What?
- 哦, 那很简单  - 怎样?
- We get squashed.
- Oh. What! Well, come on!
- 我们会被撞死  - 噢, 什么! 那, 赶紧啊!
Right!
对了
They've switched over the circuits.
The lift's working!
他们换了电路板, 电梯可以工作了!
How splendid. Bring it up here.
很棒! 开到这里来吧
Bring it up to the sixth floor.
把它开到六楼
(CLANGING)
Hey, that's not what I think it is, is it?
嘿, 那不是我想的那样, 是吗?
I'm very much afraid it is. Come on!
恐怕是的, 快点!
- We'll never make it!
- Yes, we will! Come on!
- 我们到不了了  - 能, 我们可以的. 快点!
(LIFT CLATTERS)
What's happened?
发生了什么?
It's stopped! They must be checking.
它停掉了. 他们肯定在检查
Come on, they may guess where we are
and come after us.
快点, 他们可能在猜我们在哪儿, 会来追我们
The engineer's certain...
工程人员很肯定...
- The shaft terminates in the roof, doesn't it, Packer?
- Yes, sir.
- 这个竖井通到顶楼, 是吧, Packer?   - 是的, 先生
- Why didn't you think of that?
- I'll get them!
- 你怎么没想到这个?  - 我去抓他们!
Call me when you do, Packer.
I'll be in my office.
抓到了就叫我, Packer. 我就在我的办公室等
And please don't fail this time,
there's a good fellow.
这次请不要失败了, 那里面有个好家伙
They've started it again!
他们又开动了
Hurry, Jamie! Hurry!
快点, Jamie! 快!
- Come on, Jamie.  - Wait a minute, Doctor.
- 跟上, Jamie  - 等一下, 博士
No, come on. Let's see where we are.
不, 快点. 我们来看看我们在哪儿?
- Now where?  - Down there.
- 现在去哪儿?   - 下去那边
JAMIE: Oh, no!
噢, 不是吧!
Well, we can't go down the lift again, can we?
我们不能再搭电梯下去了, 对不?
Hello. There's a fire escape. Come on.
哈罗, 这里有个消防出口. 快来
Oh, Packer, you do disappoint me.
噢, Packer. 你真让我失望
They must have got down the fire escape, sir.
他们肯定沿着消防通道下去了, 先生
And, of course, you didn't think
to have a guard on that!
而且, 你当然没有想到派一个人守在那里!
- Well, normally...
- You're a stupid incompetent!
- 只是, 通常...  - 你真是愚蠢无能!
I want that Doctor!
我要那位博士!
Put the whole compound on alert!
Have every available guard on the job!
整个园区发布告警! 把所有警卫都派到这个事情上!
Find him, Packer! Find him!
找到他, Packer! 找到他!
(ALARM BLARING)
- GUARD: You two! Over here!
你们俩, 过来!
Get those two girls over to
the main administration building! Move!
把这两个女孩儿带到主行政大楼去! 走!
- Zoe and Isobel.
- Wait. We'll follow in a few moments.
- 是 Zoe 和 Isobel  - 等等,  我们一会儿再跟上
Take them inside. Central block, tenth floor.
带她们进去. 中央区域, 10楼
(ROTORS WHIRRING)
Could be the Brigadier's lot.
Call them up for help.
可能是准将的人. 请求他们帮助
No, no, not yet.
We've got to rescue the girls first.
不, 不, 先不要. 我们得先把这两姑娘救出来
Tenth floor, central block. Come on.
10楼, 中央区域. 快点
There's a lot of unusual activity, sir.
Guards everywhere.
有很多异常活动, 长官. 到处都是警卫
It looks like some sort of emergency.
看起来像是某种紧急状况
BRIGADIER: Any sign of the Doctor and the boy?
有博士和那个男孩儿的踪迹吗?
No, sir. None at all.
没有, 长官. 完全没有
Right,Jimmy. Get out of the area and stand by.
好, Jimmy. 撤离那个区域, 待命
Right, sir. Will do.
收到, 长官. 马上执行
- All units, please, Sergeant.
- Yes, sir.
- 请接所有小组, 中士  - 是, 长官
Go ahead, sir.
开始吧, 长官
This is the Brigadier. All units, stand by.
我是准将. 所有小组, 准备
Full penetration of red sector imminent.
即将全面突入红区
Hey, Zoe.
嘿, Zoe
Zoe, look!
Zoe, 看!
- Doctor!  - Jamie!
- 博士!   - Jamie!
Yes, Doctor, come in.
是的, 博士, 进来
Brigadier, I think we shall require
a little assistance in a few moments.
准将, 我想再过一小会儿我们需要一点援助
Are you in trouble?
你们遇到麻烦了?
No, but we shall need help.
You have a helicopter in the area?
还没有, 但我们需要帮助. 你在这个区域有直升机吧?
Yes.
是的
I wonder, have they a rope ladder on board?
我在想, 他们那里有绳梯吗?
Yes, I'm pretty sure they have. Where are you?
是的, 我非常肯定他们有. 你们在哪里?
We're just going up to the roof
of the main building.
我们正要上到主楼的楼顶去
That is the central block on the north side.
主楼在北边的中央区域
That should give your helicopter cover
should there be any ground fire.
那个位置可以给直升机一点遮挡, 说不准地面会有火力袭击
- Have you got that?
- Yes, I've got that.
- 你收到了吗?   - 是的, 我收到了
Over and out.
完毕, 挂断
You were lucky, dead lucky.
你们很幸运, 非常幸运
He said it would be
a simple rescue operation. Simple.
他说将是一个简单的营救行动. 简单
But what about my uncle?
但我的叔叔怎么办?
- They've still got him prisoner.
- Don't worry, Miss Watkins.
- 他还处于他们的监禁之下  - 别担心, Watkins 小姐
As soon as we return to base,
I'm going to raise hell and get some action.
等我们一回到基地, 我就增派人手, 展开一些行动
You think they'll listen to you now?
你觉得他们现在会听你的了?
No one, not even Tobias Vaughn, can go as far
as trying to shoot down one of my helicopters.
没人能够猖狂到想把我的直升飞机打下来, 就算 Tobias Vaughn 也不行
Oh, I wish I'd had my camera.
I could have got a fortune for those pictures.
噢, 我期望我带了相机来, 本来有幸可以拍到一些照片的
Yes, it was a pity.
是的, 真遗憾
That would have clinched it
as far as the Ministry are concerned, sir.
那样的话就可以在国防部那里实捶他们了, 长官
Don't worry, Jimmy. Billy Rutlidge
will have to take some action now.
别担心, Jimmy. Billy Rutlidge 现在必须采取些行动了
Why am I being taken back to London?
为什么把我带回伦敦?
What about my niece? What's happened to Isobel?
我的侄女怎么样了? Isobel 她发生了什么?
I tell you, she's perfectly safe.
我告诉你, 她相当安全
I want to see her!
我想要见她!
So you shall.
那你会的
When you've finished working on your machine.
只要你先完成那台机器
Do as I ask and you shall both go free.
按我要求的做, 你们俩都可以得到自由
You don't even expect me to believe you, do you?
你没指望我会相信你吧, 是吗
Well, you've very little choice.
只是, 你的选择很少
Now, we're going back to London.
现在, 我们要回到伦敦
There you will work on your machine
to my specifications.
你在那里要按我定的规格做出那台机器
You will have 24 hours to complete it.
你有24小时来完成这项任务
Only if you haven't finished your work by that time
如果你到那时还没有完成你的工作
would you have cause to worry about your niece.
你才有理由担心你的侄女
- BRIGADIER: Mean anything to you, Doctor?
- Possibly.
- 让你想起什么吗, 博士?   - 可能吧
How long ago were these objects first sighted?
第一次看见这些东西是在多久以前?
Reports have been drifting in
for well over a year now.
一年多以前就陆续有报告送过来
We sent up fighter planes to investigate,
but nothing ever came of it.
我们派了战斗机去调查, 但没有任何结果
The odd thing about these sightings is
这些目击事件比较奇怪的地方是
that they usually seem to disappear
somewhere over southeast England.
它们似乎通常都消失在英格兰的东南部某处
But isn't that where all those factories
and laboratories of Vaughn's are?
但那不就是 Vaughn 的工厂和实验室所在的地方吗?
Exactly.
的确
Well, obviously they bring these things,
whatever they are..
那, 显然是他们把这些东西, 不管它们是什么...
up from the factory in the country
to the London premises.
从乡村的工厂带到了伦敦市区
That's where we're going to find the answer.
那就是我们要去寻找答案的地方
You mean go back to Vaughn's place?
你是说回到 Vaughn 的地盘去?
I don't think that's wise, Doctor.
You've been lucky so far.
我觉得那样并不明智, 博士. 你们目前已经够幸运的了
Aye, if you think I'm going back inside there...
是. 如果你觉得我打算回到那里面去...
Jamie, we have to find what is inside these crates.
Jamie, 我们必须搞明白那些板条箱里面是什么
Brigadier, have you got a map,
including the London premises?
准将, 你有地图吗, 包含伦敦市区的?
- Yes, yes, I think so. Sergeant Walters!
- Sir?
- 有,  有, 我想是有. Walters 中士!  - 长官!
- Jamie, I'm afraid I was right!  - Eh?
- Jamie, 恐怕我说对了  - 呃?